Jawwad Uddin





A strong problem-solving background, testament to studying a Masters in Mechanical Engineering. Tenacity to learn new things make me the perfect asset for companies in the software engineering sector. My interest to pursue a career in this field stemmed from the initial exposure of creating a program to compute the solution to a particularly strenuous problem in one of my university modules. I had found extreme joy in self learning python to complete such a task. It was apparent a career in software development would be the logical progression for me thereafter as it involves problem solving, which I am good at, but more importantly, it is something I very much enjoy. I regularly go to the gum and participate in outdoor activities as health and fitness is a big part of my life.

SUMMARY

I attained a Masters in Mechanical Engineering at University College London (UCL) and I am currently training as a Full Stack Developer with futureproof. At university, I was selected to represent UCL as the project manager of the 4th year Hydro-Racing team which involved designing a propulsion system for a catamaran to compete in the international MSEBC (Monaco Solar and Energy Boat Challenge) 2021.

I have experience working as a part-time A-Level tutor for 5 years which has developed my organisational and communication skills. Having just graduated from university, I have begun the futureproof course as there is no doubt that this is the career path I wish to excel in. I am now looking forward to put my problem-solving skills into use by developing solutions to problems using programming.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Futureproof | Software Engineer | March 2020 - present

GitHub: https://github.com/JawwadUddin

- 13-week bootcamp covering the main areas of web development, including JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Databases, and Python.
- Built a variety of web-apps, both individually and in small DevOps teams.

Study Support | Senior Tutor | July 2017 - present

- Head of A-Levels department. Current 3 students are now predicted A*/A instead of B/C for A-levels.
- 2018 All my students achieved 7-9 for GCSE's, an improvement of up to 2 grades for some of them.
- Liaison with parents to inform on student progress after managing and creating tailored progress plans for each student.

Canary Wharf Group (CWG) | Summer Intern | June 2017

- Shadowed Howard Dawber (Managing Director), researched, wrote summary reports for him as well as attended meetings.
- Representing Canary wharf in community events to improve their public perception.
- Actively supervised and partook as a team leader for the annual CWG Go-Kart build competition.
- Successfully applied for sustainability award for Roof Garden after meeting with Michael Bryant (Operations Executive at Canary Wharf Station).

EDUCATION

University College London (UCL) | September 2017 - July 2021

Mechanical Engineering (MEng) - 1st

City of London Sixth Form/ LEA/LIS Secondary School | September 2011 - July 2017

A-Level: Mathematics - A*, Further Mathematics - A, Physics - A, Chemistry - A

GCSE: 11A* 2A

TECHNICAL SKILLS

| HTML | CSS | JavaScript |
|------|-----|------------|
| | | |

Node.js, Express, Jest GitHub/ Git API